I finally found you a subordinate.
你的下屬人選終於確定了
She was an excellent bank clerk.
她是個優秀的櫃員
A teller?
也就是負責櫃檯事務的人？
-Is something wrong? -No.
-怎麼了嗎？ -沒事
When I was at the branch office,
我在分行的時候
I met a troublesome bank teller.
有碰過一個令人頭痛的櫃員
Hanasaki!
花咲！
Mr. Soma.
相馬前輩
Oh. Do you know each other?
咦，你們兩個認識嗎？
Yes, we worked together at the Nakano Branch.
是的，我們曾在中野分行共事過
Thank you very much.
請多多指教
That's when you visit branches
分行稽核班就是到發生問題的各分行
with problems and give them assistance, right?
稽核並給予指導，是嗎？
Don't say unnecessary things during the branch inspection.
在分行那邊絕對不要多嘴
What?
欸？
Think of it as a different company.
把它當作不同的公司看待
Why would you come to give us guidance over some missing passbooks.
為了遺失帳本這種小事就叫稽核員來
That damn manager gets me so mad!
氣死我了，可惡的分行經理！
Watch it.
別說得太過分
It's only a simple teller job.
區區櫃員的工作都做不好
With all due respect…
恕我直言
Shut up.
閉嘴！
I will not.
我不要！
Thank you.
謝謝
CONGRATULATIONS
（百年好合）
-Mika. -You're so beautiful.
-實花 -妳好美
Thank you.
謝謝大家
-She's so lucky. -Mika is adorable. She looks so happy.
-真羨慕 -實花超可愛，看起來好幸福
She got herself a catch! He's from the bank's Finance Department.
她真會挑老公，對方是融資課的
He's on the right track, with the transfer to the New York Branch.
而且要被調去紐約分行，升遷真順利
I was there at the party when they met.
他們認識的時候我也在場
-I wonder why-- -The next number is 48.
-真想不通 -接下來是48號
Bingo. I got bingo!
賓果…我中了！
I'm not getting anything.
我什麼都沒中
-Mai. -Yeah?
-舞 -嗯？
I'm going to be crossing over…
其實我也快要…
to that side as well.
成為人妻了！
What? Why?
咦？什麼？
What's happening? How?
為什麼？怎麼發生的？
Of course she's here…
她果然也來了
This is why I hate weddings between bank colleagues.
所以我才不喜歡參加同事的婚禮
BRANCH MANAGING DEPARTMENT BRANCH INSPECTION KEN SOMA
（分行管理部稽核班，相馬健）
It'll be downhill from here.
今天是他們幸福的最高峰了
Right?
對吧？
Before we got married,
結婚之前
my wife said, "I love how you're so tall,"
我老婆說：“你好高好帥”
but now she says, "You're in the way."
但現在說：“你太高了好擋路”
I understand! Sometimes when I get home earlier than usual,
我懂，我有時候提早回家
my family starts sighing.
家人看到還會嘆氣
Soma, I'm so jealous of your single life.
相馬，好羨慕你還是單身
Are you being sarcastic? I've already got an X-mark.
在挖苦我嗎？我已經留過不良紀錄了
With both work and marriage.
工作跟婚姻都是
-Stop laughing. -Next number is seven.
-別笑了 -接下來是七號
It's a lucky seven.
幸運七號
-Seven. -I got it.
-七號… -中了
-I don't have it. -I don't either.
-沒有 -我也沒有
What? A marriage agency?
婚姻介紹所？
Yeah. I couldn't bring myself to tell other people until now,
對，有點難以啟齒，就沒跟大家說了
but I've been actively looking for a marriage partner.
我很努力參加各種結婚活動
I see. And then?
是喔，然後呢？
Honestly, I wasn't feeling any connections with the people I was introduced to.
一開始我跟被介紹的對象都不來電
So I got tired of it all, and I was ready to give up
覺得好麻煩，想放棄的時候
but that's when I met "the one."
我就和他相遇了
-I see. -The next number is 15.
-這樣啊 -接下來是15號
I got bingo! Bye, Mai!
賓果，我先過去啦
I won!
我中了！
I'm so behind.
我完全落後大家
By the way, I heard that you're
對了，你現在的同事
partnered with a young lady.
是不是一個年輕女生？
-Really? -Yes, she's young
-真的嗎？ -她雖然年輕
but she's no lady.
但完全沒有女生的樣子
-How lucky. I only work with men. -Me too.
-真好，我同事都男的 -我也是
I'd rather work with men than with her.
我寧願跟男生共事，也不要跟她
Next number is 31.
下一個號碼是31號
I got it!
中了！
-Bingo… -Bingo!
-賓果… -賓果
-What?
-出現賓果了 -咦？
-Yay. -Soma, you got bingo, right?
-是我 -你不是賓果了嗎？
-What? No, I didn't. -We have a bingo too!
-嗯？沒有啦 -這裡也有一個賓果
-Stop it. -We have a bingo.
-別鬧了啦！ -這裡有賓果！
Mr. Soma.
相馬先生
Stop it.
別鬧了
Congratulations. Here is…
恭喜兩位，你們的禮物是
your prize!
這個！
It's so big.
好大隻
-It's so heavy. -Excuse me.
-好重 -不好意思
-Can you take me to Monzen-nakacho? -Sure.
-我要到門前仲町 -好的，請上車
Monzen…
門前仲町…
Bye… I'll call you later.
我先走了，再聯絡
Mr. Soma, I want a ride too.
相馬先生，請送我一程
What? Wait.
咦？等等…
-Wait… -I didn't want to ride the train.
-搞什麼… -我不想抱著娃娃
-Not carrying this thing. -Hold on.
-去搭電車 -等一下啦
I'm also heading to Monzen-nakacho. What a coincidence.
我也剛好要到門前仲町
Seriously?
真的假的？
Please take us to Monzen-nakacho.
請送我們到門前仲町
Thank you very much.
謝謝
This is your house?
這是妳家？
Yes.
對
-This is your house? -Hanasaki.
-這是妳家？ -這裡有寫“花咲”
Seriously?
真的假的…
And you?
你住在哪裡？
-That apartment. -What?
-那棟公寓 -什麼？
You were living that close to me? I had no idea.
我都不知道我們住這麼近
If I knew I wouldn't have moved here.
知道的話，我就不會搬來了
-Hi Dad, I'm back. -Hey, Mai.
-爸，我回來了 -舞
-Welcome back. -Nice to meet you. I'm Soma.
-妳回來啦 -你好，我是相馬
Nice to meet you. I'm Mai's father.
你好，我是舞的爸爸
-You should've told me he was coming. -What?
-怎麼不先告訴我你們要來？ -什麼？
I have to prepare myself beforehand.
爸爸也需要一些心理準備啊
It's not like that. Mr. Soma is from the bank…
不是那樣，你搞錯了，相馬是銀行…
Bank! Good for you, you're one step closer to your dream.
銀行！太好了，妳又離夢想更進一步
-What? -To become a wife of a banker.
-什麼？ -成為銀行家的妻子
What? That was never my dream.
我才沒有這種夢想
-Stop saying weird things. -Don't be shy.
-不要再講奇怪的話 -別害羞了
It seems like he's a lot older.
他看起來年紀大很多
-That's okay as long as there's love. -It's not like that.
-但有愛就能跨越障礙 -爸，你誤會了
You're so lovey-dovey with matching stuffed animals.
你們還抱著娃娃，真恩愛
Lovey-dovey? It's not like that, Dad!
恩愛？爸，你真的誤會了
Dad? Did you just call me Dad?
爸？你剛剛叫我爸嗎？
-Uh… -That makes me happy.
-對… -我好開心
I've always wanted a son.
我一直都想要一個兒子
-It's not-- -I've wanted a son.
-不，那只是… -我想要一個兒子
How old are you? Maybe we're not so far apart in age.
你幾歲？我們沒差太多吧？
-What year were you born? -1971.
-你是哪一年出生的？ -1971年
What year of the Showa era?
-是昭和幾年？ -昭和的話是…
You've got it all wrong.
就說你誤會了！
Got what wrong?
誤會什麼？
Mr. Soma is just my boss.
相馬先生是我的上司
Boss?
上司？
I'm so sorry.
抱歉，真是失禮了
You should've told me sooner.
-不會 -妳怎麼不早講？
You weren't listening to me.
是爸爸都沒在聽我講話
Ugh…
真是的
TOKYO DAIICHI BANK HEADQUARTERS
（東京第一銀行總部）
What? Pineapple-shaped cookies and pancake mix?
鳳梨形狀的餅乾跟鬆餅加在一起？
Don't worry about bringing back gifts.
不用特地帶伴手禮回來
Concentrate on enjoying your honeymoon
好好享受難得的蜜月旅行吧
and have a romantic time with your husband.
跟老公甜蜜度假
Bye, have fun.
掰掰，好好玩喔
Hello, Mr. Shindo and Mr. Kodama.
辛苦了，真藤部長、兒玉次長
Who are you?
妳是？
-I'm Hanasaki. -Hanasaki?
-我是花咲 -花咲？
The Branch Inspector.
稽核班的
It seems like Yajima from Kayabacho Branch caused you some trouble.
茅場町分行的矢島給你們添麻煩了
It's wrong to bully female employees
為了減少支出
in order to make them quit and cut costs.
欺負女職員逼她們離職 一點也不合理
-Shut up. -No, I won't.
-閉嘴！ -我不要！
Just because you're a boss,
不能因為你是上司
doesn't give you the right to ruin their lives.
就肆意破壞下屬的人生
I wouldn't say they caused us trouble.
添麻煩什麼的，您言重了
Excuse me.
我先告退了
-Wait. -Yes…
-等一下 -是
Is this yours?
這是妳的嗎？
Seems like you left it behind.
妳好像忘記拿了
Sorry, I got it this morning,
抱歉，這是今天早上
but I was not reading this during the meeting--
剛好在車站拿到的，我沒在會議上…
Goodbye.
再見
Thank you.
先告退了
Why did I drop this?
我怎麼會忘記拿這個？
Did that female employee solve that
茅場町的事件
incident at the Kayabacho Branch?
是那個女職員解決的？
It wasn't just Hanasaki, since she was with her boss Soma.
不只花咲，還有她的上司相馬
Hanasaki.
花咲…
I'll remember her.
我會記住她
BRANCH INSPECTION
（分行稽核班）
HIGH RATE OF SUCCESS
（結婚成功率極高！）
HW BRIDAL ENROLLMENT SYSTEM
（入會申請）
What? Enrollment fee?
咦？入會費…
It's 150,000? That's expensive.
15萬？好貴啊
How expensive.
好貴啊
You're so easy to read.
妳也太容易被看穿了吧？
What?
什麼？
Let me guess. "I attended my friend's wedding,
反正一定是參加了同事的婚禮
and now I feel like I need to hurry."
覺得自己也該著急了吧？
That's not true. I was just taking a look.
才沒有，我只是看一下而已
What is it?
怎麼了嗎？
You don't have to be a banker's wife?
不當銀行家的妻子沒關係嗎？
You heard that yesterday?
你都聽到了？
I heard it all because he was talking so loud.
妳講那麼大聲，我當然聽到了
Please forget about what he said.
才不是那樣，請你忘記吧
My dad was saying that, but that's not what I'm looking for.
都是我爸亂講的，我沒有那種夢想
Oh no,
哎呀
we got a troublesome case.
有麻煩的工作來了
Can you go to the Aoyama Branch?
你們可以去青山分行嗎？
-What happened? -We received a letter of protest.
-發生什麼事了？ -我剛才收到抗議文
Letter of protest?
抗議文？
Wait,
等一下
there are so many of them.
這麼多人？
Yes, it's from female members
她們都是“葛蘭婚友社”
of a marriage agency called Grand Marriage.
婚姻介紹所的女性會員
They're not being introduced to anyone.
卻完全沒有被介紹任何對象
But why are we getting that complaint?
這跟我們有什麼關係？
The Aoyama Branch is financing that company.
因為青山分行有融資給那間公司
They're protesting to the bank for financing them?
他們對融資給黑心企業的銀行抗議？
That's right, Soma.
沒錯，不愧是相馬
Banks get that kind of protest?
銀行會被抗議這種事？
It's very rare.
幾乎沒發生過吧？
They're probably taking it out on us.
她們應該是想找對象出氣
Please make sure there are no problems with the details.
總之，先去調查交易跟融資過程
-Check the transactions and loans. -Will do.
-有沒有發生問題 -我明白了
Oh,
對了
the manager at the Aoyama Branch is in the Shindo faction.
青山分行的分行經理是真藤派的
So please make sure you don't do anything to upset him.
請不要冒犯到他，拜託了
-Okay. -All right.
-是 -好
I've got lots to do.
我好忙…
What? Two million yen enrollment fee?
入會費要兩百萬？
Male member's annual income is 30 million yen.
男性會員年收入三千萬以上
Are they serious?
真的有可能嗎？
-It's obviously suspicious. -I agree.
-太可疑了吧？ -就是說啊
I can't believe women are willing to pay
居然有女性
two million yen in order to marry someone of high status.
為了嫁入上流社會，願意支付兩百萬
I can't believe they fall for this.
通常都會起疑心吧？
That's true when you look at it objectively,
客觀角度看來是這樣沒錯
but one can lose their sense of judgement when they're in a rush.
但是心急的時候根本無法冷靜判斷
What is it?
怎麼了？
It's okay, Hanasaki.
別擔心，花咲
I'm sure you'll find a great man.
妳一定會找到好男人
I'm not talking about myself. It's them!
不是我，是她們啦
But it's so vindictive of these people to send
但是因為找不到結婚對象
letters of protest to the bank just because
就發抗議文到銀行
they can't get married.
也太瘋狂了吧？
What?
咦？
-Hey, Hanasaki. -Yes?
-花咲 -是
A marriage agency is where
婚姻介紹所
they introduce you to possible candidates for marriage, right?
是介紹結婚對象的地方，對吧？
-Yes, of course. -That doesn't seem to be the case here.
-是的 -這間公司
Look.
顯然不是這樣
"Not been introduced to a single person for six months after enrollment"?
“入會半年都沒有介紹對象”？
That goes for all 313 members mentioned here by name.
這裡313位會員都一樣
That's awful.
真過分
This is a scam.
這算是詐欺吧？
BRANCH MANAGER HAYAO NITTA
（分行經理，新田隼夫）
Mr. Soma.
相馬先生！
What are you doing? Let's go.
你在做什麼？快走吧
AOYAMA BRANCH
（青山分行）
We're Branch Inspectors Soma and Hanasaki from headquarters.
我們是總部稽核班的相馬跟花咲
-Branch Manager Nitta, please. -Yes.
-要找新田經理 -是
How very kind of the Branch Inspectors to come here
總部稽核班的人特地過來
from headquarters.
真是不敢當啊
Not at all.
哪裡
But I'm surprised to see you
但我好驚訝
doing this kind of a job, Soma.
相馬你居然在做這種工作
I moved to headquarters three months ago.
我三個月前被調到總部的
The former ace of the Finance Department is now a Branch Inspector, huh.
之前的融資課王牌居然到稽核班了
And your partner is a female to boot.
而且還跟女同事搭擋
Now,
我們是來了解
as for the details regarding your loan to Grand Marriage--
葛蘭婚友社的融資情形
They sent in claims for the marriage agency to the bank?
他們把抗議婚姻介紹所的事送到銀行
They're barking up the wrong tree.
找錯對象了吧？
You guys must really have extra time on your hands,
連這種事都認真處理
to be checking up on things like this.
你們應該很閒吧？
Um…
那個…
But we can't simply ignore this amount of
但是有這麼多人抗議
protest letters.
我們也不能置之不理
These are just women taking their anger out on us because they can't marry.
這只是結不成婚的女性拿銀行出氣
There are no problems with our loans.
跟我們的融資沒有關係
With all due respect…
恕我直言…
Sorry, but handle the rest with Sugishita, since he's in charge.
抱歉，接下來請找負責融資的杉下
I have plans, so I'll be leaving.
我還有事，先離開了
Wait. Wait a moment.
請等一下
Excuse me.
不好意思
I wasn't done speaking.
我還沒把話講完耶
I'm very sorry.
真是抱歉
No worries.
不會
Um… but
不過
I don't think we have any problems with our loans.
我們的融資是沒有問題的
Their business plan was properly made as well.
他們的營運計劃書寫得很完善
I'll take a look.
我看一下
LOAN APPROVAL DOCUMENT
（融資申請書）
It's been about six months since Grand Marriage started their business.
葛蘭婚友社半年前才開始營運
I think it will take time to start seeing good results.
還沒促成婚姻也是情有可原的事
-That's not it. -What?
-不是的 -什麼？
The female members are not protesting because they haven't found a match.
會員們抗議的是從沒被介紹過對象
They're protesting the fact that they haven't been introduced to a single person
這半年來，會員完全沒有被介紹
for six months.
認識的對象
What do you mean?
這是怎麼回事？
Everyone who signed here, has paid
連署的每一個人
the enrollment fee but they haven't
都有付入會費
been introduced to anyone yet.
但是都沒有沒被介紹對象
That can't be…
怎麼這樣？
If that's true,
如果屬實
this is a fraud.
這就是詐欺了
Which would mean
也就是說
that this bank gave a helping hand to the fraud.
我們銀行把錢貸給了詐欺公司
One moment. I will go talk to Grand Marriage.
抱歉，我去一趟葛蘭婚友社
Mr. Soma, we should go too.
-我們也去吧 -嗯
Mr. Sugishita.
杉下先生
-We'll go too. -Thank you.
-我們也一起去 -好，麻煩你們了
Grand Marriage was created six months ago by Eiji Munakata
葛蘭婚友社是宗方英司半年前
after he left a big consulting firm.
從大型顧問事務所出來獨立開的公司
When he worked as a consultant,
他還在當顧問的時候
he rebuilt companies that were about to go under,
多次讓陷入困境的公司起死回生
and successfully built new businesses.
也成功創造新的事業
-That's why we had hope in him. -And the loan?
-所以我們對他很有信心 -融資金額多少？
-Fifty million yen. -I see.
-五千萬元 -了解
Here it is.
就是這裡
What?
咦？
-What? -That can't be!
-什麼？ -怎麼可能？
Mr. Sugishita, where's the office?
辦公室在哪裡？
Behind here.
就在後面
What's happening?
這是怎麼一回事？
Excuse me. What are you doing?
不好意思，你們在做什麼？
Who are you?
你們是誰？
We're from Tokyo Daiichi Bank.
我們是東京第一銀行的人
We came to talk to Mr. Munakata.
有事情想找宗方社長
There is no one here,
宗方社長不在這
including Mr. Munakata.
這裡完全沒有人了
I'm Shimamura from the police department.
我是警局的島村
Why is the police here?
警察來這裡做什麼？
This company has been charged with alleged fraud.
這間公司被控告有詐欺行為
-Fraud… -It seems like Mr. Munakata
-詐欺… -看來那位社長
took 600 million yen from the members
是把總共六億的會費
and disappeared.
捲款逃走了
What?
什麼？
What do you mean?
你說什麼？
I'm very sorry.
非常抱歉
Apparently, Grand Marriage
葛蘭婚友社
had gathered over 300 female members,
募集到三百名女性會員
but they didn't have a single male member.
但是一位男性會員都沒有
Therefore, it was a fraudulent scheme meant to deceive its members
所以從頭到尾收會費的目的
by taking their enrollment fees.
就只是為了詐欺
What's happening, Sugishita?
杉下，怎麼會這樣？
Weren't you in contact with Mr. Munakata?
不是你負責跟宗方社長聯繫的嗎？
I talked to him the other day, but I had no idea…
前陣子跟他聯絡時，還沒出現異狀
How was the loan screening process?
融資審查過程都沒有問題嗎？
There were no problems!
這還用問嗎？
We screened the application according to the business plan they brought.
我們根據對方提出的營運計畫書審核
It was done properly.
一切按照合法流程
Then it would mean that
但是營運計畫書的內容
their business plan was fabricated.
全部都是他們捏造的
Sugishita!
杉下！
You were in charge. How did you not catch that?
你是負責人，怎麼沒有發現？
I'm very sorry.
非常抱歉
The 50 million yen we loaned will be unrecoverable.
我們貸出的五千萬可能無法回收
If that happens,
這樣的話，我們分行
it will wreck our branch.
會受到極大影響
Do you understand that, Sugishita?
杉下，你明白嗎？
It was my fault for putting you in charge.
我不該把這件事交給你的
-But Manager… -What?
-但是，經理… -怎麼？
Never mind.
沒事
Listen.
聽好了
You have to collect that 50 million yen no matter what.
不管怎樣，都要把五千萬拿回來
If you can't get it,
拿不回來的話
you have to take responsibility.
一切都是你的責任！
No way…
怎麼這樣？
It's all about the results.
結果才是重要的
That's banking!
這就是銀行
Yes.
是
He didn't have to say it in such a way.
他不用把話講得那麼難聽吧？
"That's banking"? What does he mean?
“這就是銀行”？什麼嘛？
Isn't that ridiculous?
太不合理了
That's who he is.
他就是這樣的人
Mr. Soma, you know Mr. Nitta?
你和新田經理之前就認識了嗎？
Six years ago, when I was at the Marunouchi Branch,
六年前我還在丸之內的融資課時
Mr. Nitta was the manager.
新田是課長
I see.
這樣啊
He hasn't changed at all.
他這個人一點都沒有變
Oh, Mr. Sugishita.
杉下先生
Where are you going?
你要去哪裡？
I'm going to Mr. Munakata's house.
我要去宗方社長的家
-What? -Um…
-什麼？ -這…
He ran away with 600 million yen. I doubt he'll be home…
捲走六億元的人應該不會待在家
But I have to retrieve that 50 million somehow.
但無論如何我都得把五千萬拿回來
-Mr. Soma, I'll go with him. -Hanasaki!
-我和他一起去 -花咲！
That's not your job. Our job is to--
這不是妳該參與的，我們的工作是…
To check if the loan was screened properly or not, right?
調查融資過程是否有缺失，對吧？
We can't make that decision right now.
但是這樣下去，我們無法得到結論
I'll be off.
我出發了
Hey!
喂！
There she goes again.
真是的
Mr. Sugishita.
杉下先生！
I'll go with you.
我和你一起去
Thank you.
謝謝
The number you have called
您撥的電話
-is no longer in business… -Damn it.
-目前無法接聽 -可惡
What's happening?
到底是什麼情況？
I think this is it.
好像就是這裡
There are no clues as to where he might be?
完全沒掌握到他的行蹤？
Yes, nothing as of now…
是，目前什麼線索都沒有
It would be trouble if he already left the country.
要是讓他逃出國就麻煩了
It seems like he's no longer here.
他果然不在家
Yeah.
對
If Mr. Munakata never appears again…
如果讓宗方社長逃走的話
It will be hopeless.
一切就完了
What?
咦？
That person…
那個人…
PRESIDENT OF GRAND MARRIAGE EIJI MUNAKATA
（社長，宗方英司）
That man! Isn't he Mr. Munakata?
那個人是不是宗方社長？
-What? -That man.
-什麼？ -就是他
Mr. Munakata!
宗方社長！
What's happening? Please explain!
現在是什麼情況？ 請你說明，宗方社長！
Ouch.
好痛
Wait!
等一下！
What?
什麼？
I'm telling you to stop!
我叫你等一下，混蛋！
Hey!
停下來
Oh darn…
可惡…
Ouch.
好痛
-Are you okay? -Yeah…
-你還好嗎？ -沒事
Please use this.
這個給你用
Thank you.
謝謝妳
We were so close.
真是不甘心
He was right in front of us.
他都出現在面前了
Yes.
是啊
We can't back down now.
我們不能就這樣放棄
Mr. Sugishita, do you know of any place that Mr. Munakata
你知道宗方社長平常會去
might go to?
哪些地方嗎？
No.
不清楚
What about people that might know where he'd be?
那有誰會知道他的行蹤嗎？
Oh…
啊
-You know someone? -No.
-你想到什麼了嗎？ -不…
You do, right?
是誰？
-Mr. Sugishita! -Ouch!
-杉下先生… -好痛…
Sorry.
抱歉
Um…
我想…
It's Branch Manager Nitta.
是新田經理
Mr. Nitta and Mr. Munakata are good friends?
新田經理跟宗方社長很熟？
Yes, they often went
對，他們常常
golfing and eating together.
會去打高爾夫球、一起吃飯
I see.
這樣啊
In fact, the loan for Grand Marriage,
其實，貸款給葛蘭婚友社
was an order by the Branch Manager.
是分行經理的指令
What?
什麼？
Mr. Nitta.
分行經理
It's a new business so I think we need to
申請融資的公司才剛成立
examine it more carefully.
應該要更仔細地調查
What are you saying?
你說什麼？
You know Mr. Munakata's abilities from when he was a consultant, right?
你知道宗方社長 在當顧問時的能力有多好吧？
It's his business. It won't fail.
他成立的公司一定沒問題
But it's still a new business transaction for us.
但對我們來說仍然是新客戶
-An unsecured loan would be… -It's fine.
-如果不要求擔保… -沒問題的
We're financing Mr. Munakata's abilities and future prospects.
我們是把錢交給 宗方社長的能力和未來
Just hurry up and submit the request for approval.
趕快把申請書送出去審核
But manager…
但是，經理…
Are you going to oppose the Manager?
你打算跟我作對嗎？
Remember that I can easily decide
你給我注意一點
what to do with you at my own discretion.
你的命運可是掌握在我手中
Don't worry.
別擔心
If something happens, I'll take responsibility.
發生問題的話，我會負責
Yes.
是
He said that he'd take responsibility?
他說他會負責？
But he told you
但是剛才他說
that it's your responsibility.
是你的責任？
What he's saying is the exact opposite.
他講的話完全相反
Why didn't you speak up when he said that?
聽到他那樣說，你怎麼不反駁？
I had no choice.
我也沒辦法
He can easily ship people off that do not listen to him.
分行經理隨時能讓不聽話的下屬走人
But still…
但是…
I'm going to become a father soon.
我的小孩快要出生了
I can't go against the Branch Manager.
我不能跟分行經理作對
Thank you.
謝謝妳
I wonder what's going to happen.
事情會變得怎樣呢？
Hey.
嗨
Mr. Soma!
相馬先生！
What are you doing here?
你在這做什麼？
Here's the ultimate turnip.
久等了，究極蕪菁料理來囉
I've been wanting to eat this.
我超期待這道菜的
I've been curious ever since I saw the sign for this the other day.
之前在菜單看到時就很想吃
Thank you.
我開動了
It's delicious.
好好吃！
That makes me happy, Mr. Soma.
真開心你喜歡
Please stop by every day.
歡迎你每天光臨
We epicureans have lots in common.
我們都熱愛美食，應該很合得來
I'll definitely come back.
我一定會常來的
It seems like you two became close in a short span of time.
你們很快就熟起來了呢
I heard you were dumped on New Year's.
我聽說妳一月被別人甩了？
-Dad? -It was a slip of the tongue.
-爸 -我不小心說出來了
How did you let it slip?
怎麼會不小心？
And I've told you.
而且我早就說過
-I wasn't dumped, we broke up. -The outcome is the same.
-我不是被甩，是分手 -結果還不是一樣？
It's completely different.
完全不一樣好嗎？
You're so lucky to have a dad like this.
妳有這樣的爸爸真幸運
Oh, really?
為什麼？
He nags, has a sharp tongue, and can never keep a secret.
愛撈叨、嘴巴壞，又守不住秘密
I'm sure it was hard
他一定也很不容易
for him to raise a daughter like you all by himself.
一個人把像妳這樣的女兒帶大
A daughter like me…
像我這樣的女兒…
-You're right, Mr. Soma. -Thank you.
-就是說啊 -不好意思
My wife passed away when she was ten.
我太太過世時，她才十歲
I had never done housework, so I had to start from zero.
我完全沒做過家事，從零開始學起
And you started to cook?
做菜也是那時才開始？
Yes, I didn't cook before that.
對，我之前是全職上班族
But that awakened me to the world of cuisine,
但我也因此展開料理之路
and I opened this restaurant.
開了這間店
You're incredible.
真是太了不起了
Mr. Soma, I know that you and I will get along very well.
我就知道我們會合得來
Yeah!
耶！
-Please enjoy. -Thanks.
-慢慢享用 -好
I see. That's not good.
這樣啊，真傷腦筋
At this rate, our 50 million yen will be unrecoverable.
這樣下去五千萬就收不回來了
You heard how Mr. Nitta said the loan for Grand Marriage
剛才你有聽到新田經理說
was all Mr. Sugishita's responsibility, right?
這筆融資都是杉下的責任，對吧？
-Yeah. -But that's not true.
-嗯 -但那不是事實
The manager forced Mr. Sugishita to submit the loan and put him in charge.
是分行長逼杉下強行通過融資 還叫他負責
Then he said that he would take responsibility.
說如果發生問題，他會負責
So that's what happened, huh?
果然是這樣
You knew?
你不驚訝嗎？
It's something Mr. Nitta would do.
果然像新田會做的事
But isn't it unfair?
這樣不對吧？
It's the Manager's fault, but he's unscathed.
明明是分行經理的錯 卻不用受到責罰
But Mr. Sugishita has to take the blame,
反而是杉下要負起責任
and he might be shipped off.
不然可能會被踢走
Credit goes to the boss. Mistakes to the subordinates.
功勞歸給上司，過錯下屬承擔
What is that unreasonable slogan?
那是什麼不合理的說法？
That's common knowledge at a bank.
這是銀行的常識
What? That's unacceptable.
什麼？我完全無法接受
Quiet.
小聲點
I'm sorry.
啊，不好意思
First of all, I get a bad vibe from that Branch Manager.
那個分行經理給人很討厭的感覺
-What? -It's the condescending way he speaks.
-嗯？ -他用藐視別人的方式說話
And he has such a flashy watch even though he's a bank employee.
而且身為銀行員，卻戴花俏的手錶
His watch… was flashy?
手錶…是嗎？
Yes!
對啊
Why do those people get promoted?
為什麼他那種人可以升職？
-What are you doing? -I'm sorry. I'll do it.
-妳在做什麼？ -抱歉，我來整理
Please sit down.
不用麻煩，你請坐
Sorry. Once she gets riled up,
抱歉，她進入暴走狀態
she loses all reasoning.
完全察覺不到周圍的事
Yes, I know.
是啊
Mr. Soma, she can be a handful
相馬先生，我的女兒這麼不成材
but please take care of her.
請你多多照顧她了
Uh… yes.
啊…好
MARRIAGE AGENCY CHARGED WITH ALLEGED FRAUD
（婚姻介紹所涉嫌詐欺）
PRESIDENT OF THE COMPANY HAS DISAPPEARED
（社長失蹤）
Mr. Sugishita won't be forced to take responsibility for this,
杉下先生真的要為這件事
will he?
負起責任嗎？
A loan is approved after many people sign
融資申請過程，不是也有經過
the proposal, right?
很多人的審核嗎？
Yeah.
是沒錯
Oh?
咦？
Branch Manager Nitta from the Aoyama Branch?
那不是青山分行的新田經理嗎？
I see.
原來如此
That's a troubling situation, Nitta.
新田，這件事很棘手
I'm very sorry.
真的十分抱歉
If we approved a loan to a company running a fraud,
銀行把錢借給有詐欺嫌疑的公司
it would be considered as a compliance violation.
會被認為違反規定
Yes.
是啊
In addition to that, if the 50 million yen is unrecoverable,
而且還會損失五千萬的貸款
you will have to face the consequences of that.
你勢必要為此承擔後果
Grand Marriage was a new contract,
葛蘭婚友社是新成立的公司
so I was concerned that it wasn't examined well enough,
所以我擔心審查過程過於鬆懈
but my subordinate Sugishita believed in Munakata's abilities.
但是我的下屬杉下 十分信任那個社長的能力
So I believed him and put him in charge.
我也就放心交給他處理了
I see.
這樣啊
I will make him take responsibility.
我打算讓他負起責任
It will be painful for me to do so,
要讓疼愛的下屬走人我也很不捨
but if I go easy on him, it won't set a good example.
但不做處置，就沒辦法樹立良好典範
I see.
我了解了
That's fine.
這樣也好
Yes.
是
Nitta.
新田
I'm expecting great things from you.
我對你有很高的期待
Don't disappoint me.
別讓我失望了
Thank you. I will keep that in mind.
謝謝您，我會銘記在心
Are you serious?
真的嗎？
The Manager said the loan for Grand Marriage
分行經理說葛蘭婚友社的融資
is Mr. Sugishita's fault?
全都是杉下的責任？
Yes, he did.
對，他說會讓他負起責任
I guess that can't be helped.
這也沒辦法
It's become such a big issue now.
事情變得越來越嚴重了
I feel sorry for Mr. Nitta since he
有這種麻煩下屬
has to deal with such subordinates.
我真替新田感到可憐
It's time for my meeting.
我要去開會了
Listen, don't tell anyone about what I just told you.
聽著，剛才我講的話不准說出去
-Sure. -I'm so busy.
-是 -我好忙…
This is horrible. It's all lies.
真是過分，全都是謊言
The Manager forced Mr. Sugishita to submit the loan.
明明是分行經理逼杉下進行融資的
I'm going to object to Mr. Nitta.
我要去找分行經理抗議
It's a waste of time.
沒用的
Nothing you say will get to him.
妳跟他講什麼都沒有用
Why do you give up so easily?
為什麼這麼輕易就放棄？
Both you and Mr. Sugishita.
你和杉下都是
"Credit goes to the boss. Mistakes to the subordinates."
功勞歸給上司，過錯下屬承擔
That's unacceptable.
這完全不合理
Are we not allowed to point out what's wrong at this bank?
我們不能指出銀行做錯的地方嗎？
It can't be helped!
沒有幫助的
What you're saying is correct.
妳講的的確沒錯
Everyone knows that.
大家心裡都很清楚
But
但是
no matter how correct it is,
無論有多正確
there are some things that don't apply at a bank.
有些事在銀行就是行不通的
You may not know that because you've always been a teller.
妳之前是櫃員，可能不曉得
With all due respect…
恕我直言
is it the rule at a bank to keep quiet when we see someone
看到有人被不合理的事壓迫
suffering from injustice?
什麼都不做，就是銀行的常識？
When things become inconvenient,
情況變得不順利時
everyone says "bank this," "bank that."
大家都說銀行本來就是怎樣
Are banks that special?
銀行是這麼特別的存在嗎？
What are you doing?
妳在做什麼？
You're from Branch Inspection.
妳是稽核班的…
I heard that Manager Nitta from the Aoyama Branch was here.
我聽說青山分行的新田經理有來過
Mr. Nitta already left.
他已經離開了
I see.
這樣啊
What business do you have with Mr. Nitta?
妳找新田經理有什麼事？
Nothing. Thank you very much.
沒事，謝謝你
Hanasaki.
花咲
BRANCH MANAGING DEPARTMENT DIRECTOR SHINJIRO KARASHIMA
（分行管理部，辛島伸二朗部長）
What's the matter?
怎麼了？
Mr. Karashima.
辛島部長
I see. That's what Soma said, huh?
原來如此，相馬說了這樣的話啊
Yes.
是的
I think he sees his past self
我想他在杉下身上
in Mr. Sugishita.
看到自己的過去了吧
AOYAMA BRANCH NITTA / ISHIKAWA / SUGISHITA
（青山分行，新田、石川、杉下）
If it's unrecoverable,
拿不回來的話
it's your responsibility!
一切都是你的責任！
What happened to him in the past?
相馬先生之前發生了什麼事？
I guess I can tell you since you work with him.
你們是同事，告訴妳也無妨
Did you know he was in the Finance Department at Marunouchi Branch?
你知道他之前在丸之內的融資課嗎？
Yes, he said he worked under Mr. Nitta.
嗯，聽說他是新田的下屬
Yes, that's the time.
對，就是那個時候
A business he was overseeing went bankrupt
他負責的一間公司破產
and lost 100 million yen.
導致一億元的損失
One hundred million?
一億元？
In order to take responsibility for that, he was transferred
為了負起責任，他從融資課
from the Finance Department to the Sales Division.
被調去營業課
Basically, he got an X-mark
他已經留下不良記錄
and fell off his career path.
也遠離升遷之路了
But there was a rumor back then saying,
但是那時候有傳聞說
"Soma had to
“相馬是幫
take responsibility in place of his boss, Nitta.
上司新田背負責任
Nitta was the one that originally
推進這筆融資的人
proceeded with the loans to begin with."
是新田”
NOTICE OF TRANSFER
（人事異動）
Please wait a minute.
等一下
Manager Nitta, that's an account that you handed over to me.
那是新田課長說要進行的融資
You didn't listen to me
我建議要重新審核
when I asked you to reconsider it.
但是您並沒有採納我的意見
-Why do I have to-- -You're in charge of this account.
-為什麼我得… -這筆融資的負責人…
You.
是你
There's nothing else to be said.
其他都不用多說
PERSON IN CHARGE - SOMA
（負責人：相馬）
All that matters is the result.
結果才是重要的
That's a bank for you.
這就是銀行
Everything regarding this issue is your responsibility.
這次的事件全都是你的責任
They're the only ones who know the truth.
傳聞是真是假，只有當事人知道
But that incident
但是那次事件
changed his life as a banker.
絕對改變了他身為
That's for sure.
銀行員的人生
I see.
原來是這樣
But I'm surprised to see you
但我好驚訝
doing this kind of a job, Soma.
相馬你居然在做這種工作
The former ace of the Finance Department is now a Branch Inspector, huh.
之前的融資課王牌居然到稽核班了
And your partner is a female to boot.
而且還跟女同事搭擋
These are just women taking their anger out on us because they can't marry.
這只是結不成婚的女性拿銀行出氣
If you can't get it,
拿不回來的話
you have to take responsibility.
一切都是你的責任！
All that matters is the result. That's a bank for you.
結果才是重要的，這就是銀行
BRANCH INSPECTION
（分行稽核班）
I'm sorry about earlier.
剛才很抱歉
I shouldn't have said that.
我不應該那樣說話
It's fine.
沒事，不就跟平常一樣嗎？
Um…
那個…
-Um… -What is it?
-那個… -怎麽了？
Mr. Soma.
相馬先生
Let's take revenge.
我們來復仇吧？
What are you saying?
妳在說什麼？
There's something I noticed about Branch Manager Nitta.
我發現有關新田經理的一件事
-What? -Mr. Sugishita said something.
-什麼？ -杉下說
That he recently bought a house in the downtown area.
分行經理最近在市中心買房子
He bought a foreign car too.
還換了進口車
And?
所以呢？
Do you think he's getting a share of the money
他是不是也有拿錢？
from Grand Marriage?
葛蘭婚友社的錢
That's why he pushed for the loan.
所以他才強行通過融資
But we have no proof.
可是我們什麼證據都沒有
Proof…
證據…
Oh, look at this.
啊，有了
"Wonderful business. I'd like to support it. Nitta."
“很棒的事業，我會支持你”
He wrote this, right?
這是新田寫的吧？
Would this prove that he forced the loan proceedings?
能證明他強行通過融資嗎？
No, this wouldn't be enough.
不，這證明不了什麼
What else is there…
還有什麼…
Something else…
其他的…
-Sorry. -What are you doing?
-抱歉 -妳在幹什麼？
What?
嗯？
Is this…
這該不會是…
What is it?
怎麼了？
CUSTOMER INFORMATION DATABASE
（客戶資料）
AKASAKA BRANCH
（赤坂分行）
Just as I thought.
果然沒錯
What is it, Hanasaki?
怎麼了？
Mr. Soma, please take a look at this.
你看一下這個
-What is it? -Members of Grand Marriage.
-到底是怎麼了？ -葛蘭婚友社的會員中
Among them is a customer I knew when I worked at the Akasaka Branch.
有我在赤坂分行時的客戶
How did you remember her name?
妳居然還記得名字
Remembering the customer's name is part of a teller's job.
記得客戶資訊是櫃員的基本職責
But just one person…
但是只有一個人…
There's at least ten people just within this list.
不，這頁名單中就有十人
TOMOMI KUWABARA AKASAKA BRANCH JUNKO MIYAGAWA AKASAKA BRANCH
（川口美香、宮川純子；赤坂分行）
NAOMI TANIGUCHI AKASAKA BRANCH MAYUMI YOKOYAMA AKASAKA BRANCH
（赤坂分行）
Is this a coincidence?
這是巧合嗎？
Hanasaki.
花咲
Let's check them.
這313人
-All 113 names. -Yes.
-全都調查一遍 -是
-Give me half of the list.
-分一半名單給我
At this rate,
這樣下去
50 million yen will become unrecoverable.
五千萬遲早會無法回收
Yes.
是
Sugishita,
杉下
are you prepared?
你做好覺悟了嗎？
Sugishita!
杉下！
Excuse me.
不好意思
Why are you here?
你們有什麼事？
We're here to see you, Branch Manager Nitta.
我們有事想和新田經理說
Unlike the Branch Inspectors, I'm really busy.
這邊可不像稽核班那麼閒
We're having an important discussion about
我們正在討論回收五千萬
the 50 million yen loan. Right, Sugishita?
這件重要的事，對吧？杉下
We have an important discussion too.
我們也有重要的事
Branch Manager Nitta,
新田經理
it's about the crime you have committed.
你所做的是犯罪行為
What?
什麼？
Crime?
犯罪？
What are you talking about?
你到底在講什麼？
You deliberately pushed ahead with the loan for Grand Marriage
你刻意推進葛蘭婚友社的融資
because you had a reason to do so.
是有其他意圖的吧？
What?
什麼？
That's why you didn't listen to Mr. Sugishita
所以你才會無視
when he suggested
衫下的建議
examining the account more carefully.
不願仔細審查
What are you talking about?
你在胡說什麼？
I can't waste my time on this nonsense.
我沒時間陪你閒扯
Get out.
出去
That's too bad.
真遺憾
I was hoping
我以為
you would confess on your own.
你會自己承認
I said get out.
我說出去！
These are
這個是
313 signatures of female members at Grand Marriage.
葛蘭婚友社313位女性會員的連署
When we
我們對照過
compared these names with our bank's client database,
她們的姓名和本行往來的客戶資料
205 people out of 313 listed on here,
發現其中約三分之二
had something in common.
共205人有共通之處
They have an account at our bank.
她們都是我們銀行的客戶
We're a large bank. That's not surprising at all.
我們是大型銀行，這沒什麼好奇怪的
You're right.
沒錯
But that's not all.
但不只是這樣
They're all single women between 30 and 45 with
她們全都是年收入八百萬以上
an annual income of over eight million yen
存款五百萬以上的
and five million yen in balance.
30到45歲未婚女性
Grand Marriage is a high-end marriage agency.
葛蘭婚友社是高級婚姻介紹所
They had clients that could afford
她們都是付得起兩百萬會費
to pay the two-million-yen enrollment fee.
有錢有地位的會員
Lastly, there is another big common factor.
最後還有一件事
Their accounts
她們的帳戶
are all in either Aoyama, Akasaka, or Shibuya.
都開在青山、赤坂、澀谷
Just those three branches.
只有這三間分行
There are over 160 branches within the city,
光是東京都內就有160間分行
but all 205 members are clients at the three
205名會員的帳戶卻都在
branches located near Grand Marriage.
葛蘭婚友社附近的分行
Is it a coincidence?
這難道是巧合嗎？
And your point?
妳想說什麼？
Our bank's personal information was leaked.
有人洩露銀行的客戶資料
We had the System Department look at the records of searches
我們請工程部從資料庫調查
made on our database.
搜尋記錄
Female women between 30 and 45,
30歲至45歲的未婚女性
who opened an account at either Akasaka, Aoyama or Shibuya,
在赤坂、青山、澀谷分行開戶
with over five million yen in their account.
年收入五百萬以上
There was one person in our bank who had
符合以上條件
searched for all those criteria
搜查過這些資料的
on our database.
只有一個人
Employee identification number 9806451.
員工號碼9806451
Branch Manager Nitta, it's you.
新田經理，就是你
HAYAO NITTA AOYAMA BRANCH
（青山分行，新田隼夫）
That's wrong. It's not me.
他們搞錯了，不是我
You sold the data to
你把客戶資料
Mr. Munakata, right?
賣給宗方社長了吧？
Based on that data, Grand Marriage persistently
葛蘭婚友社利用那些資料
solicited them by calling and messaging,
用信件和電話不斷推銷
to acquire its members.
讓她們成為會員
You took part in a crime
你參與這起犯罪
that troubled many women!
害許多女性受害！
I didn't know that it was fraud!
我不知道是詐欺
How did this happen?
怎麼會變成這樣？
Mr. Nitta.
新田先生
Until now, whenever a problem arose, you made your subordinates
一直以來，無論發生什麼問題
take the responsibility,
你都把責任推給下屬
and that's how you came this far.
所以才能苟延殘喘至今
But you will have to take
但是這次的責任
responsibility for this one.
你沒辦法再推給任何人
Credit goes to the boss,
功勞歸給上司
mistakes to subordinates.
過錯下屬承擔
If that's common sense at the bank,
如果這是銀行的常識
that kind of common sense can…
這些常識…
kiss my ass!
都去吃屎吧！
That's all.
就這樣
-Thank you. -Not at all.
-謝謝你們 -不會
Well…
我想
I need to do my best without giving up.
我也要繼續努力不放棄
That's right. You're going to become a dad soon.
沒錯，你都快當爸爸了
Yes.
對
"Kiss my ass" huh…
“都去吃屎吧”
I'm sorry for cursing.
抱歉，講髒話了
I don't usually curse. Right?
我很少這樣，對吧？
Oh, come on.
別這樣
I'm serious. I don't usually say things like that.
我說真的，我很少那樣講話
I was just a little frustrated, but I'm usually all smiles.
剛才只是意外爆發 我平常都笑臉迎人
As for the data breach of our customer's information,
對於洩露客戶資訊一事
we deeply apologize to our customers,
造成客戶、股東和所有關係者
shareholders, and everyone involved,
極大的困擾和擔憂
for causing a great deal of inconvenience and trouble.
我們致上最深的歉意
Mr. Munakata confessed everything,
宗方社長自首了
and we may be able to recover the 50 million.
我們應該能收回五千萬
What about the female members?
這樣啊，受害的女性會員呢？
It won't be a full return,
雖然無法拿回全額
but they will get a portion of it back.
但能拿回部分費用
-I'm glad. -Yes.
-太好了 -是
But I can't believe how these problems occur
真沒想到那兩個稽核員
wherever those Branch Inspectors go.
到哪都會出問題
Yeah.
對啊
But they end up solving each incident,
但最後事情都有解決
so those two might be a very good pair.
那兩人意外地是對好搭擋呢
I can't believe
真不敢相信
Nitta damaged Tokyo Daiichi Bank's trust
新田會做這種事，還讓銀行的信用
this badly.
受這麼大損傷
Disciplinary dismissal was appropriate.
嚴懲解雇是正確的處分
Yes.
是
He was receiving money from them too…
沒想到他居然也有拿錢…
Even though Mr. Nitta was being favored by you--
雖然有您在背後關照
Who was favoring him?
你說誰關照他？
What?
咦？
He wasn't cut for greater things.
他只不過是個本性惡劣的傢伙
Yes.
是
But…
不過
seems like those Branch Inspectors stirred up trouble again.
這又是那兩個稽核員弄出來的事吧？
Yes.
對
It seems like
看來
we can't give them free rein to do what they want.
不能再讓他們為所欲為了
Yes.
是
I'm glad Mr. Sugishita didn't get terminated.
杉下沒有被處分，真是太好了
Yeah.
嗯
His wife can concentrate on her baby without any worries.
他的太太可以安心待產了
That's right.
沒錯
Family is a wonderful thing, isn't it?
有家庭真好啊
You have to get married first.
妳得先結婚再說
That's right.
也是
What should we have for lunch today?
今天的午餐要吃什麼呢？
Our inspection site today is the Odawara Branch,
今天要到小原田分行稽核
and Odawara is known for… fish cakes.
說到小田原…就是魚餅了
You're still a rookie. Those are for souvenirs.
那是伴手禮吧？妳這個菜鳥
Oden.
關東煮
Seafood rice bowl.
海鮮丼
Deep fried mackerel!
炸竹莢魚！
-That sounds good. -You think so too?
-炸竹莢魚不錯呢 -妳也覺得嗎？
-We have similar tastes. -Only with food.
-我們很合得來呢 -只有在食物方面
-Oh! -What?
-啊！ -嗯？
We'll miss the train. Let's run.
電車要來了…糟糕，我們跑去吧
Wait. Hold on a second.
喂，等一下！
Deep fried mackerel!
炸竹莢魚！
Wait.
等一下！
-Support? -As a teller.
-支援？ -妳不是櫃員嗎？
I'm getting excited.
我好興奮
Make them work harder.
給他們大量工作，別心軟
Finish this up.
先把這些處理一下
I came here to get bullied?
我們是來被霸凌的嗎？
Just do it.
快點做事！
I'll have to fight back.
我想我別無選擇，只能接下挑戰
I've been troubled because of these incompetent people.
妳知道我為了這些無能的人 受了多少罪嗎？
Everyone here is not incompetent.
這裡沒有無能的人
Subtitle translation by: Lili Morita
字幕翻譯：李瑜